Ross Anderson

Second year Computer Engineering at McMaster University

Email: ross34anderson@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ross34anderson

Website: violettides.github.io Mobile: 289-527-5576

Summary

 2 years of skills in designing electromechanical parts using CAD and EDA alongside 4 years of technical drawing skills.

 Knowledgeable of various 3D printing and CNC technologies through exposure of modifying G-code and building a laser CNC from scratch.

 Excellent problem solving and programming skills developed from time spent as head of my high school's advanced coding team, spearheading multiple major projects.

Professional Experience

Ciena Corp. | Hardware Design Engineer

May 2023 - Aug. 2023

- Drove the design and productization of 5 bleeding edge optical interconnect solutions, doubling effective speeds and reducing connector size by 40% enabling 400g datacenter connectivity.
- Conducted application verification testing on 25 interconnect solutions, utilizing lab test equipment and measurement techniques like VNAs and Oscilloscopes to assess performance and product reliability.

Longo Brothers Fruit Markets Inc. | PPF Clerk Aug. 2019 - Sept. 2022

- Delivered exceptional customer service in a fast-paced kitchen environment, honing communication skills and ensuring customer satisfaction.
- Developed strong problem-solving abilities by efficiently managing customer orders and resolving issues, demonstrating adaptability and critical thinking skills.

Projects

McMaster Rocketry Club

Sept. 2023 - May. 2023

Designed an ESP32-based data-logging PCB in KiCad to provide a
platform that will introduce future first-year students to the software
and ECAD aspect of the club.

Desktop Graphic Equalizer

Mar 2023 - Aug. 2023

- Designed an op-amp based 5-band graphic equalizer using Altium for under \$110 with an extruded aluminum housing.
- Features a true bypass relay for noiseless operation, balanced RCA inputs/outputs, and carefully selected audio grade components.

Arduino-Controlled Laser CNC

May 2023 - Aug. 2023

- Point Built a CNC machine from scratch capable of engraving wood for under \$150.
- Designed custom mounting plates and hardware using Autodesk Fusion360.Used filament-based 3D printing to rapidly prototype potential designs.

Skills

Electrical/Software

- Altium Designer, Cadence, and KiCad used for multiple personal projects as well as backplane PCB design at Ciena.
- JavaScript used to code an educational training app for volunteers at a non-profit healthcare organization.
- 3

CAD

- SolidWorks and Fusion360 used on various projects involving FEA and GD&T
- 2
- 3

Mechanical

- 1
- 2
- 3

Education

- 1
- 2
- 3